Finding Aid for the Slee Lecture Recital Recordings, 1957-1975
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Slee Lecture Recital no. 70, February 2, 1973, 1973-02-02, 2 10 inch reels; Baird Recital Hall Preservation files: ubmu0062_070_01_01.wav, ubmu0062_070_02_01.wav (Box 6, Reel 082-083)
  Performers: Jesse Levine, viola; Eiko Ito, flute; Amron Chodos, clarinet; Richard Trythall, celesta; Dennis Kahle, percussion; Henry Rubin, violin; David Gibson, violoncello; Jan Williams, conductor
  Work number: ubmu0062_070_05
  Original cassette number: SLR 324
  Viola in my life III
  Performers: Jesse Levine, viola; Richard Trythall, piano
  Duration: 7:26
  Work number: ubmu0062_070_06
  Original cassette number: SLR 325
- Slee Lecture Recital no. 71, April 15, 1973, 1973-04-15, 2 10 inch reels; Baird Recital Hall Preservation files: ubmu0062_071_01_01.wav, ubmu0062_071_02_01.wav (Box 7, Reel 084-085)
  Work number: ubmu0062_071_04
  Original cassette number: SLR 329
  Wolff, Christian, 1934-
  For piano 1 (1952)
  Performers: Barbara Warren, piano
  Duration: 9:58
  Work number: ubmu0062_071_07
  Original cassette number: SLR 332
  Burdocks (1970-71)
  Performers: Members of Mr. Feldman's Music 608 Class; Members of the Center of the Creative and Performing Arts
  Duration: 29:40
  Work number: ubmu0062_071_05
  Original cassette number: SLR 330
  Nine (1951)
  Performers: Gerald Soffer, trumpet; William Lane, horn; Donald Miller, trombone; Petr Kotik, flute; Amron Chodos, clarinet; Wendel Haver, violoncello; David Gibson, violoncello; Jeffery Kowalsky, celesta; Peter Gena, piano; Jesse Levine, conductor
  Duration: 4:21
  Work number: ubmu0062_071_02
  Original cassette number: SLR 327
  Suite I (1954)
  Performers: William Appleby, prepared piano
  Duration: 16:45
  Work number: ubmu0062_071_01
  Original cassette number: SLR 326
  Lecture: Opening remarks for concert of music by Christian Wolff
  Work number: ubmu0062_071_06
  Original cassette number: SLR 331
  Lines (1972)
  Performers: Jacquelynne Leonard, Loren Pearson, violins; Delmar Stewart, viola; Wendel Haver, violoncello
  Duration: 24:90
  Work number: ubmu0062_071_03
  Original cassette number: SLR 328
  Duo for violins (1950)
  Performers: Jacquelynne Leonard, Loren Pearson, violins
  Duration: 5:13
- Slee Lecture Recital no. 72, September 29, 1973, 1973-09-29, 2 10 inch reels; Baird Recital Hall Preservation files: ubmu0062_072_01_01.wav, ubmu0062_072_02_01.wav (Box 7, Reel 086-087)
  Work number: ubmu0062_072_01
  Original cassette number: SLR 333
  Lecture: Introduction by Morton Feldman followed by introduction by Luis De Pablo
  Performers: Morton Feldman, lecturer, with Luis de Pablo
  Work number: ubmu0062_072_02
  Original cassette number: SLR 334
  Pablo, Luis de
  Imaginario II
  Performers: Tape played: Sudwestfunk Orchestra, Baden-Baden, Ernest Bour, conductor
  Duration: 13:14
  Work number: ubmu0062_072_03
  Original cassette number: SLR 335
  Yo lo vi
  Performers: Tape played: O.R.T.F. Chamber Choir, Marcel Courand, conductor
  Duration: 17:33
  Work number: ubmu0062_072_04
  Original cassette number: SLR 336
  Quasi una fantasia
  Performers: Tape played: Philharmonic Orchestra, O.R.T.F., Richard Dufallo, conductor
  Duration: 24:36
  Work number: ubmu0062_072_05
  Original cassette number: SLR 337
  Condicionado
  Performers: Eberhard Blum, alto flute
  Work number: ubmu0062_072_06
  Original cassette number: SLR 338
  Reciproco
  Performers: Eberhard Blum, flute; Thorkell Sigurbjornsson, piano; Andrew Ziemba, percussion
  Duration: 5:38
- Slee Lecture Recital no. 73, December 14, 1973, 1973-12-14, 1 10 inch reel; Baird Recital Hall Preservation files: ubmu0062_073_01.wav, ubmu0062_073_02.wav (Box 7, Reel 088)
  Work number: ubmu0062_073_02
  Original cassette number: SLR 340
  Symphonies for seventeen brass instruments
  Performers: Tape played: Ars Nova Ensemble, Marius Constant, conductor
  Duration: 12:10
  Work number: ubmu0062_073_03
  Original cassette number: SLR 341
  Soledad interrumpida, electronic music (1971)
  Note: Tape realized by the composer. Program inserted in container.
  Work number: ubmu0062_073_01
  Original cassette number: SLR 339
  Lecture: Introduction to concert of music by Luis de Pablo
  Performers: Luis de Pablo, lecturer
  Work number: ubmu0062_073_04
  Original cassette number: SLR 342
  Por diversos motivos (1968)
  Performers: Kai-Ning Chiang, soprano; Yvar Mikhashoff, piano; Nils Vigeland, Claudia Hoca, piano duo; Winifred Black, Jane Bane, Jan Mack, Yong Sook Won, sopranos; Claudia Kelly, Ann Stimson, altos; Leslie Kleen, Norbert Osterreich, tenors; Peter Gena, Andrew Stiller
  Duration: 22:20
  Note: Program inserted in container indicates Luis De Pablo provided a spoken introduction to this piece.
- Slee Lecture Recital no. 74, February 19, 1975, 1975-02-19, 2 10 inch reels; Baird Recital Hall Preservation files: ubmu0062_074_01_01.wav, ubmu0062_074_01_02.wav, ubmu0062_074_02_01.wav (Box 7, Reel 089-090)
  Work number: ubmu0062_074_01
  Original cassette number: SLR 343
  Birtwistle, Harrison
  Lecture: Introduction to concert of music by Harrison Birtwistle
  Performers: Harrison Birtwistle, lecturer
  Duration: 18:10
  Work number: ubmu0062_074_02
  Original cassette number: SLR 344
  Refrains and choruses (1957)
  Performers: Judy Kaufman, flute; Paul Schlossman, oboe; Andrew Stiller, clarinet; Beye Fyfe, horn; Bruno Eberspacher, bassoon
  Duration: 8:33
  Work number: ubmu0062_074_04
  Original cassette number: SLR 345
  La plage: Eight arias of remembrance (1972)
  Performers: Isabelle Ganz, voice; James Pyne, Edward Yadzinski, Heather Johnson, clarinets; Joseph Kubera, piano; Donald Knaack, marimba
- Slee Lecture Recital no. 75, March 23, 1975, 1975-03-23, 2 10 inch reels; Baird Recital Hall Preservation files: ubmu0062_075_01_01.wav, ubmu0062_075_02_01.wav (Box 7, Reel 091-092)
  Work number: ubmu0062_075_01
  Original cassette number: SLR 346
  Performers: Harrison Birtwistle, lecturer, with Morton Feldman
  Note: Index cards inserted in containers.
  Work number: ubmu0062_075_02
  Original cassette number: SLR 347
  Triumph of time
  Duration: 27:10
- Slee Lecture Recital no. 76, October 14, 1975, 1975-10-14, 2 10 inch reels; Baird Recital Hall Preservation files: ubmu0062_076_01_01.wav, ubmu0062_076_01_02.wav, ubmu0062_076_02_01.wav (Box 7, Reel 093-094)
  Work number: ubmu0062_076_04
  Original cassette number: SLR 351
  Jolas, Betsy
  Mots (1961, rev. 1963). First section
  Work number: ubmu0062_076_01
  Original cassette number: SLR 348
  Lecture: The voice and its function
  Performers: Betsy Jolas, lecturer
  Work number: ubmu0062_076_02
  Original cassette number: SLR 349
  L'oeil egare dans les plis de l'obeissance au vent (1961). Sleep
  Duration: 2:11
  Work number: ubmu0062_076_03
  Original cassette number: SLR 350
  Dans la chaleur vacante (1963). Excerpt
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Music--20th century
Genres
Lectures; Sound recordings; Audiotapes
Associated Material
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Slee Lecture Recitals Catalog, 1957-1976
Mus. Arc. 62
This is the HTML inventory of the cassette collection but includes all programmed works, even if not recorded. Currently there is a link to summaries of some of the lectures.
Slee Visiting Professor in Music Papers, 1957-1993
Mus. Arc. 22
The collection chiefly consists of correspondence between thirty-two composers being considered or invited to fill the position of Slee Visiting Professor in Music at the State University of New York at Buffalo. It also contains clippings pertaining to the composers.